[Music]
Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we've got
another lesson all about food and eating.
So today we're going to talk about all the
tools that we use when we're at the table.
So what we use when we're eating.
That's right so let's take a listen to
today's dialogue and when we come back
we'll talk about some
of these words and some
of the great phrases
you're learning today.
[Music]
Henny can you set the table?
Well I'm sure what are
we having for dinner?
So I need to put
anything out in particular?
Well make sure to put out
the pepper and salt shakers.
I don't know if your
brother is coming tonight
so set an extra
place mat just in case.
Okay should I use the fancy silverware?
Yeah go ahead, forks, spoons and knives.
I roasted some meat so be sure to
put out some steak knives as well.
I'll also set some cups and
sauces for some coffee after dinner.
Henny have you seen our soup bowls?
They're in the cupboard where you
keep the gravy bowl and serving dishes.
Just be careful because the
wine glasses are also there.
[Music]
All right we're back
so now let's take a look
at a couple of words
in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So our first word is a very important one.
You might have heard it
before the word is silverware.
Okay silverware now
this means that it's usually
made something that's
made out of silver right?
It could be. Maybe traditionally it's made
out of silver but it doesn't have to be.
You could have wooden
silverware or other metals.
It's basically the things
that you use to eat food with.
Okay so we're going to
take this as a category.
Silverware are all the
tools that we use to
eat food with and in this so for example
a fork is some a part of a silverware.
It's a kind of silverware fork.
A fork is the one that
you usually put in your
mouth with a piece of
lettuce or meat or something.
Okay so it's pointy it
has like four little points.
Now the one that we use to have desserts
or to have soup with we call that a spoon.
A spoon that's right so to eat
yogurt or ice cream you use a spoon.
And finally to cut things you use a knife.
Okay so in the dialogue we saw the plural
form knives but singular it would be knife.
That's right and sometimes there
are foods that are very very hard to cut.
For example steak is very hard to
cut because it's it's a tough meat.
And so in that case we
use a steak knife to cut it.
Okay so we have a knife or a steak knife.
Steak knife more specifically
is used to cut meats.
All right so these are three kinds
or actually four kinds of silverware.
Of course there are other kinds
but those are the most important.
After that we have something that's
important for making your food taste better.
So what if I want to add salt or pepper?
What are those things called?
Those are called salt and pepper shakers.
We saw them in the dialogue that we need
to put out the pepper and salt shakers.
So the little thing where you
keep the salt is called a shaker.
That's right because the
action the verb is to shake.
That means moving your hand up and down
so some salt will fall out onto your food.
Exactly so usually it's
only salt and pepper that
we keep in these things
and these little shakers.
But apart from salt and pepper shakers
when all the silverware we're putting out
we're also putting out some saucers because
we're going to have coffee later on.
I'll say okay so this
normally goes together
with cups, cups and
saucers but everyone knows
what a cup is what is
a saucer? So a saucer is
this little plate that
you put under the cup
when you're having coffee
so usually that's where
you keep your spoon or
maybe the little bag of tea.
Okay so a saucer is
important because it also
helps in case you
spill some coffee or tea
so the coffee or tea doesn't go
on the ground it goes on the plate.
Exactly so that little
plate is called a saucer.
Now where do we
keep all the plates all the
silverware we usually
keep them in a cupboard?
Okay so you might
want to say cup board
because it's cup c-u-p-b-o-a-r-d that's
not right. The word is pronounced cupboard.
Okay so even though it
may seem like you should
pronounce cup board
the correct pronunciation is
cupboard. Cupboard and
a cupboard like you said
is usually in the dining
room or the kitchen
because it houses it keeps all of our plates
and bowls and sometimes our silverware.
That's right okay so
actually in the cupboard
we also have some other things, dishes,
specifically we have a gravy boat in there.
Okay so I'm not even sure
why they call it a boat but
a gravy boat is
basically a special dish.
It's like a it's like a tall bowl
with a spout so you can pour
it that keeps gravy.
So gravy is like a liquid
or a sauce that goes on
top of meat or potatoes.
I guess it kind of looks
like a boat just imagine
a boat but inside it's empty so then that's
where you put the gravy in. You pour it.
You can pour it. All right
and so we can find that.
We can also find serving
dishes which are basically
big plates or bowls
that we use when we're
having dinner at the
dinner table to keep for
example a turkey or a
roast. And specifically we
were also looking for
wine glasses. Well maybe we
weren't looking for them
but they found us because
the person getting stuff
out of the cupboard dropped
some wine glasses. These
are very very easy to break.
Wine glasses are
basically just glasses
that maybe are tall and
you drink wine out of them.
That's right so there is
a specific type of glass
usually used to drink
wine so wine glasses.
I guess normal glass that
you use to drink maybe
juice or water is
just called a glass.
Right you wouldn't say wine glass
only when you're drinking wine.
Okay so we've taken a
look at a lot of vocab here.
A lot of tools that we use at the dinner
table when we're having dinner. So let's
listen to the dialogue
again and review.
Honey can you set the table?
Sure what are we having for dinner?
Do I need to put
anything out in particular?
Well make sure to put out
the pepper and salt shakers.
I don't know if your
brother is coming
tonight so set an extra
place mat just in case.
Okay should I use
the fancy silverware?
Yeah go ahead. Forks, spoons
and knives. I roasted some meat
so be sure to put out
some steak knives as well.
I also set some cups and sauces
for some coffee after dinner.
Honey have you
seen our soup bowls?
They're in the cupboard
where you keep the gravy
boat and serving dishes.
Just be careful because
the wine glasses are
also that. Alright we're
back so now we have four key phrases that
we've prepared for you on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay so this
first phrase is very important
especially as a child your
mother or father might
ask you to do this. The
phrase is to set the table.
Okay so that's a phrasal
verb to set the table
and what does it mean if
you're asked to set the table?
It means you will put down the plates
and the silverware and the bowls so that
everything is prepared
for dinner. Okay so this is
actually what we were
doing and a complimentary
phrasal verb to this
when you're setting the
table as you said you are
putting down or putting
out the different spoons,
knives, dishes, all that stuff.
Right so the verb to
the verbal phrase to
put out means to place
down or to to make sure
that you get something
out on the table.
In this case my mother
would usually ask me to put out
extra glasses for water
okay or don't forget to
put out the wine glasses
in case for drinking
wine it just means to
place down. Exactly so just
remember that it's we
use it because all these
things that are inside the
cupboard so you have to
take them out so you
have to put them out on the
table. All right and
sometimes we may have a guest
or we may need an
extra chair or an extra seat
because we were having
company and the person in
dialogue said to set an
extra placement just in case.
Okay so place mat
is basically a piece of
plastic or maybe fabric
that you put in front
of a person when they're
at the table so it's on
the table and it's something
that protects the table
so it's small everyone
has one and the bowl
and the silver will go
on top of that place mat
but it also indicates that
that is where someone will sit.
Okay so to put out or to set out an extra
place mat means to prepare an extra place
for someone else who
will be coming so if you
have a guest for example
you'll set out an extra
place mat for him or for
her. Okay so we can say
set an extra place mat
because this is by this
we are referring that
somebody is going to sit
down at the table or
you can just simply say set
an extra place for
someone. That's right set an
extra place your older
brother is coming home
from college tonight.
Okay so we can set an extra
place for him at the
table and well in this
case we didn't know
if the brother was really
coming or not so
she said just in case.
This is a great phrase one
that you'll hear all the time
it means I'm not sure
what the result will be or
what the outcome will
be but in case something
happens or just in
case we should do this.
So for example Marco I think
it's going to rain today you
should bring an
umbrella just in case.
Okay so this is a way of saying
you're preventing something
you're prepared maybe
if it does rain you'll have
an umbrella just in
case bring your umbrella.
Okay so a lot of great
phrases there a lot of
vocab so why don't we listen
to the dialogue for the last time.
Honey can you set the
table? I'm sure what are
we having for dinner?
Do I need to put anything
out in particular? Well
make sure to put out
the pepper and salt
shakers I don't know if your
brother is coming tonight so
set an extra place Matt just in case.
Okay should I use
the fancy silverware?
Yeah go ahead, forks, spoons
and knives. I roasted some meat
so be sure to put out
some steak knives as well.
I also set some cups and sauces
for some coffee after dinner.
Honey have you
seen our soup bowls?
They're in the cupboard
where you keep the gravy
boat and serving dishes. Just be careful
because the wine glasses are also there.
All right we're back so
talking about dinner and
silverware there are also
a couple of other names
that we didn't mention
for example many people
refer to ceramic plates
as China. Yeah these are
usually the the fancy
kinds of plates and dishes
that you have in your
house. Obviously if you
have just kind of the
cheap ceramics that you
can throw away or even
paper or paper plates
those aren't very important
but at a wedding or
in a special occasion a
person or family might
receive Chinaware.
China and that is very nice,
very pretty porcelain
plates or just lacquerware.
Okay so you can call it
Chinaware which is basically
plates that are either
very fine ceramic or
porcelain as you said.
That's right or what was
the other word that you
said before? Lacquerware.
Lacquerware is a
certain kind of plate or
ceramic that has a kind
of sheen to it. It's very
got a special kind
of basically paint job.
Okay yeah because it's
always been kind of a strange
effect that a name like
China would also now be
related to plates but
apparently I guess because
Chinese porcelain is renowned as
being such high quality I guess this is why
now we just have a word for
it called China or Chinaware.
I think it actually
has to do with the
fact that the Chinese
and the old days sent sold
well most of the British
bought their porcelain
from China and so it
was very very in vogue it's
very popular and it was
basically the only thing that
the British wanted. They
just wanted all of this
China and it became a
part of the vocabulary then.
Yeah it's really strange
though that you would
call something China.
It's like I don't know any
other country that you call
something you know like French.
This is a French
or a Frenchware.
I don't know I can't think
of any. Limoj is a name
of a city in France and it's
a certain kind of ceramics.
There you go. All right so an interesting
topic there are many other tools that we
didn't mention would
like salad, fork and ice
cream, spoon and I don't
know there's so many
as sometimes if you go
to a fancy dinner you will
have maybe three spoons,
three knives, three forks
and you don't know
what to do with it.
Start on the outside and go in
that's my phone recommendation.
Exactly so we're really curious to know
what you have to say come to our website
englishpot.com if you
have any questions you
can leave them there
or if you also want to
suggest a topic for a
lesson or anything you want
just let us know. All
right we'll see you then.
All right bye!